Collection of Bookplates of Religious Orders
Yale University Arts Library
Collection of Bookplates of Religious Orders
1500-1799
BKP 102
Yale University Arts Library
0.42
(1 box)
The collection contains bookplates of various religious orders in the Christian tradition. Dating from the 16th to the 18th century, many of the bookplates represent Catholic communities or organizations in Germany.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Yale Bookplate Collection was formerly housed in Sterling Memorial Library. The collection was incorporated into the Arts of the Book Collection in 1984 and then moved to the Seeley G. Mudd Library in 1990. In 2011, it was transferred to the Robert B. Haas Family Arts Library.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains bookplates of various religious orders in the Christian tradition. Dating from the 16th to the 18th century, many of the bookplates represent Catholic communities or organizations in Germany.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Bookplates – Religious Orders. II. Bookplates – Cities. III. Bookplates – Unidentified.
The original filing system grouped materials either by religious order or by the location of specific communities and organizations. Because of the small size of this collection, this original system has been maintained and is reflected in the series divisions. Within each series, folders are arranged alphabetically.
Bookplates; Religion in bookplates; Bookplates
- Bookplates – Religious Orders, Series I
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains bookplates arranged by religious order. The various orders are arranged alphabetically.
  - Augustinian, 1615-1778 undated; 39 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Benedictine, [15??]-1796 undated; 50 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Capuchin, undated; 4 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carmelite, undated; 10 items (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cistercian, 1727-1792 undated; 13 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dominican, undated; 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Franciscan, 1706-1722 undated; 16 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Jesuit, 1595 undated; 11 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Premonstratensian, 1672-1786 undated; 13 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Servite, [16??] undated; 6 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Bookplates – Cities, Series II
  This series contains bookplates of various religious orders which are identified by location – either the city or region of specific communities and organizations. All four place names are located in Germany and are arranged here alphabetically.
  - Freiburg, 1756 undated; 8 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Magdeburg, undated; 2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Oberalteich, 1778 undated; 3 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Paderborn, 1692; 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Bookplates – Unidentified, Series III
  This series contains a small number of bookplates which were not filed by religious order or by location.
  - Unidentified, 1694-[175?] undated; 9 (Box 1, Folder 15)